Open fire!
砲撃開始！
Gloucesters?!
グロースター？
They were supposed
to be in Serupham!
セルファムにいるはずでは
Damned overgrown fake Knightmares!
でかいだけのナイトメアもどきがっ
They would have done well
to surrender at the start!
さっさと降伏すれば良かったものを
どわっ あぁ…
What?!
何？
Cornelia! Impossible!
Just one unit did this?!
コーネリア… まさか １機で？
うっ うわぁー
We've done it.
Area 18 has been established.
これで落ちたな エリア18の成立か
My Lady, about our next plan of action...
姫様 次の行動計画ですが
Forgive me for dragging you along to clean
up my foolish younger brother's mess.
すまぬ 愚弟の後始末に付き合わせて
No, My Lady. Our place is with you,
wherever that may be.
いえ 我ら 姫様のおられる所が
国でございますれば
ふっ
Area 11 won't be as easy
as our usual assignments.
エリア11は一筋縄ではいかんぞ
I agree, milady.
承知しております
うん
Yes...
I'll drive you into the open, Zero!
あぶりだしてやる ゼロ
Clovis will be avenged!
クロヴィスの仇
Jibun wo sekai sae mo
The moment when I might be able...
自分を 世界さえも 変えてしまえそうな
Kaete shimae sou na shunkan wa
To change myself and even the world
瞬間は 何時も直ぐ傍に…
Itsumo sugu soba ni
It's always right there at my side
Kakusenu iradachi to
Even as I stood still, looking at myself
隠せぬ苛立ちと
Tachitsukusu jibun wo mitsume
With undisguised frustration
立ち尽くす自分を 見つめ
Mayoi nagara nayami nagara
Feeling lost, feeling anguished
迷いながら 悩みながら
Kuyami nagara kimereba ii sa
Feeling mournful, deciding what to do
悔やみながら 決めればいいさ
Kimi ga kureta kotoba hitotsu
All it took was a single word from you
君がくれた 言葉ひとつ
Tomadoi wa kiesari
And my uncertainty vanished
戸惑いは消え去り
Karappo datta boku no heya ni hikari ga sashita
You let the light shine into what was my empty room
からっぽだった 僕の部屋に 光が射した
Miageta oozora ga
The sky I had been looking up at...
見上げた大空が 青く澄み切って行く
Aoku sumikitte yuku
Cleared and turned blue
Tozashita madowo hiraku
And I decided to throw open...
閉ざした 窓を 開く事を決めた
Koto kimeta
The windows that were kept closed
Jibun wo sekai sae mo
The moment when I might be able...
自分を 世界さえも 変えてしまえそうな
Kaete shimae sou na shunkan wa
To change myself and even the world
瞬間を 感じる今ここに…
Kanjiru ima koko ni
I feel it right here with me
THE PRINCESS AND THE WITCH
ふぅ…
ただいま
I'm home.
おかえり ルルーシュ
Welcome back, Lelouch.
なっ
おかえりなさい お兄様
Welcome home, big brother!
その様子だと
食事は外で済ませてきたな
From your appearance,
can I assume you ate out tonight?
心配しました ゼロという人の騒ぎに
巻き込まれたんじゃないかって
I was worried!
I was wondering if you were caught up
in the uproar that man Zero caused.
I tried phoning you,
but you didn't answer.
電話したんですけど 繋がらなくて
お兄様 せっかくC.C.さんが
来られたのに
Big brother?
After Miss C.C. came here, too...
は…
C.C.？
C.C.?
うっふふふっ
変わったお友達ですのね
イニシャルだけだなんて
You have such an odd friend here.
Imagine, only going by her initials!
ああ
Yeah...
ひょっとして お兄様の恋人？
She isn't your girlfriend, is she?
えっ？
将来を約束した関係だ なっ？
Our relationship involves a promise
he made for the future. Right?
はっ？
将来って… 結婚？
For the future? You mean marriage?
違う 違うって そういうのじゃなくて
だから その… 彼女は冗談が…
NO! No, it's not like that.
It's like, um... She's kidding!
嫌いだ
I hate that.
うっ
そうですか お兄様が…
I see... Big brother,
you're doing this sooner than most.
意外と早いんですね
Still, they say everyone's different,
so I suppose it's not that strange...
でも 人それぞれって言うし
おかしくは ないのかしら…
あっ
ああ 何やってんだよC.C.
濡れちゃってるよ
Oh, C.C., look what you've done!
You're soaking wet!
ほらっ 洗面所 行かないと
着替えも出してやるから
C'mon, we have to get you to the
bathroom and get you a change of clothes!
ナナリー すぐに片付けるから動くなよ
Nunnally, just stay here and I'll
get that cleaned up in a minute.
And she was kidding before.
Kidding! Just a joke!
それと さっきのは嘘だから 嘘 冗談
Who are you?!
誰だ お前は？
言ってただろ C.C.と
Didn't you hear?
She said my name is C.C....
Not that! You're...
そうじゃなくて お前は…
死んだはず… か？
...supposed to be dead?
うっ
気に入ったか 私が与えた力は？
So, do you like the
power that I gave you?
やはり お前が…
As I thought. It was you.
不満か？
Dissatisfied?
いや 感謝してるよ
No, I'm grateful.
俺のスケジュールを大幅に
前倒しして くれたんだからな
It's allowed me to drastically
advance my schedule.
Schedule?
スケジュール？
ブリタニアをぶっ壊す予定表さ
My schedule for obliterating Britannia.
動き出せるのは もう少し先になると
思っていた
I had assumed I'd have to wait a bit
longer before I could make my move.
壊せると思うのか？　その力だけで
You think you can destroy it?
Just with that power?
これがなくても やるつもりだった
I'd intended to do it without this power.
見込み通り 面白い男のようだ
Just as I expected.
This guy's fascinating...
お前 これからどうする？
軍に追われているんだろ？
What will you do now?
The military must be after you.
Only a small part of the military.
軍といっても ごく一部だけ
なら 普通に隠れているだけで十分だ
But just hiding normally
should be enough.
ここで我慢してやるよ
I'll just have to make do here.
おい 泊まるつもりか？
Hey! You expect to stay here?!
男は床で寝ろ
A real man would sleep on the floor.
そういう事じゃなく
That's not what I meant!
私が捕まったら お前も困るだろう？
My being caught would be
trouble for you as well, correct?
一緒の方が危険だ
It's dangerous for us to stay together!
野宿したら補導される
If I camp out in the open,
I'll get arrested.
お前の都合じゃなく こちらの都合を
This is about what's
convenient for me, not YOU!
しつこいのは嫌いだ
I hate stubbornness!
うっ…
You obviously aren't
bothered by much, are you?
緊張感のない奴だな そもそも
どうやって助かった
Anyway, how did you survive?
What's your story?
バックボーンは？　それにお前があの時
言っていた契約って…
And what about that
contract you said...
おやすみ ルルーシュ
Good night, Lelouch.
くっ
フクシマ コウチ ヒロシマ
Fukushima, Kochi, Hiroshima...
これで７件目ですね
あのゼロが現れてから
This makes the seventh incident
since that man Zero appeared.
ゼロに続けって 他のグループが
頑張っちゃってる みたいだね
Looks like the other groups are following
Zero's lead and putting up a real fight.
ジェレミア代理執政官は 例の
オレンジ疑惑で統率力を失っているし
Suspicions about that Orange thing have
cost Margrave Jeremiah his leadership.
器じゃなかったんだよ
おかげで警察や行政との連携もボロボロ
He couldn't handle the job.
Thanks to him, the links between the
police and the administration are fouled up.
こっちもいい迷惑だ
It's caused a fine mess for us, as well.
けっ
力を貸してくれ 藤堂！
Help them, Tohdoh!
ゼロによってブリタニアは混乱している
The Britannians are in chaos,
thanks to Zero!
今こそ我々日本解放戦線が
立ち上がる時だ
Now's the time for us in the Japan
Liberation Front to make our stand!
焦るな！
Keep your cool!
キョウトが紅蓮弐式を ゼロに
与えるというのは確定情報ではない
This isn't definite information that
Kyoto is giving the Guren Mk-II to Zero.
ゼロに こだわり過ぎると
足元をすくわれるぞ
If we pay too much attention to Zero,
we'll end up tripping ourselves up!
なあ 結局オレンジとは なんだったのだ？
So, in the end,
what was Orange, anyway?
ふっ
なんだ？
What?
人の質問には一切 答えないくせに
俺には質問するんだな
For somebody who won't answer questions,
you sure ask a lot of them.
答えたくなければ答えなければいい
私のようにな
If you don't wish to answer them,
you don't have to. Just as I don't.
ふっ…
でまかせだよ オレンジなんて
Orange was just something I made up.
ただ 同志とか言いたがる連中ほど
However, the more they may
claim to be like-minded comrades,
疑惑というトゲで簡単に
分裂するものだからな
the easier it is to divide them
by the thorns of suspicion.
ふっ
世界中がお前を探している
お前の為に世界が動いている
The whole world's looking for you.
Because of you, the world is moving.
ルルーシュ お前はこれが
見たかったのか？
Lelouch, is this what you wanted to see?
いや この騒ぎは手段に過ぎないよ
No. This uproar is simply
a means to an end.
世界はもっと大きな混乱に叩き込まれる
The world is destined
for even greater chaos.
枢木スザク一等兵 第11方面軍域
重要107号
Pvt. Suzaku Kururugi, case number
107 of the Area 11 military forces.
クロヴィス殿下殺害容疑については
証拠不十分につき釈放とする
In the matter of your involvement in the
murder of His Highness Prince Clovis,
you are hereby set free
due to lack of evidence.
どうして いきなり
What brought this on out of the blue?
どいて下さーい！
Out of the way, please!
あっ
Look out below!
危なーい！
えっ
うわっ
あの 怪我とかしていませんか？
Um, you aren't hurt, are you?
ごめんなさい 下に人が居るとは
思わなくて
Forgive me! I didn't think
there was anyone below me!
ああ いえ 僕も上から女の人が
落ちてくるとは思いませんでしたから
Um, that's okay.
I wasn't expecting a girl to come
falling down on me, either.
あら？
Oh, my!
ん？
どうかしました？
Is something wrong?
はい どうかしたんです
Yes! Something is wrong!
へっ？
The truth is, I'm being chased by bad guys.
私 実は悪い人に追われていて
だから助けて下さいませんか？
So, could you help me, please?
We can't let Orange be the one in charge when
Princess Cornelia takes up her new post!
コーネリア殿下のご着任を
あのオレンジに仕切らせる訳にはいかん
このままでは 我ら純血派の忠誠が
疑われる
At this rate, the loyalty of us Purebloods
is being called into question.
本当なのでしょうか？
ジェレミア卿が賄賂などと…
Is it true that Lord Jeremiah was bribed?
では オレンジとは なんだ？
Then what is Orange?
あ…
いずれにせよ ジェレミア卿に
後ろめたい事があるのは事実だ
In any case, Lord Jeremiah is
definitely hiding something.
何も覚えていない などと
バトレーと同じ言い訳を
Saying he doesn't remember anything...
The same lame excuse as Bartley!
ジェレミア卿も記憶が混乱している
Lord Jeremiah's memory is confused.
シンジュクでサザーランドを
奪われた者達も同じ
Just like the men in Shinjuku
whose Sutherlands were stolen...
そして…
And...
ん…
自己紹介が まだでしたね 私は…
We haven't introduced ourselves yet,
have we? My name is...
ユフィ
Euphy!
ユフィ？
Euphy?
Yes!
はい
僕は…
I'm...
ダメですよ
No, don't!
ん？
あなたは有名人なんですから
Because you're a celebrity.
枢木玄武首相の息子さん
枢木スザク一等兵
The son of Prime Minister Genbu Kururugi.
Pvt. Suzaku Kururugi!
はぁ
嘘なんでしょ 悪い人に追われてるって
You were lying before, weren't you?
About being chased by bad guys?
Meow!
にゃー
は？
にゃーにゃー
Meow! Meow! Is kitty hurt? Meow!
怪我しちゃったのかにゃ？
フゥー！
にゃー にゃにゃー
Meow, meow, meow!
ニャー
フッフッフゥ
にゃにゃー
Meow, meow!
えへっ
ふっ
ニャー
は…
うっ
あらっ
Oh, my.
遅れちゃったなぁ
待ってくれてると いいけど
We're running late.
I hope he's still waiting.
でも 本当に釈放なんですか？
But was he really released?
証拠不十分でね まあ ゼロの件では
たっぷり取り調べられたみたいだけど
They had no evidence.
Still, it looks like he was thoroughly
investigated because of that incident with Zero.
あ…
あれ？　なんで？
Huh? Why's he?
はぁ？
猫 苦手なんですか？
You have trouble with cats?
僕は好きなんですけど
I like them, but...
シャー
片思いばっかり なんです
The feeling isn't mutual.
片思いって優しい人が するんですよ
Unrequited love is the mark of a kind person.
あ…
あっ
行っちゃいましたね
He ran away.
ユフィ さっきは どうしてあんな嘘を？
Euphy...
Why did you lie to me before?
私の事 気になりますか？
Are you concerned about me?
え？　あ… はい
Huh? Uh, yeah.
じゃぁ もう少し私に
付き合って下さいな
Then accompany me some more!
あっ あ…
こうしていると ブリタニアにいるのと
変わらないですね
Being here is just like being in Britannia.
ユフィは本国から？
Are you from the homeland?
Yes! I was a student up until last week.
はい 学生でした 先週までは
先週までって… じゃあ今は？
学生って 高校生？
Until last week?
So, what are you doing now?
By student,
you mean in high school?
観光なら いつだってできるでしょ？
You can go sightseeing
any time, can't you?
えっへへっ
質問攻めですね
So many questions!
あっ すみません
Oh. Sorry...
Oh, no! I didn't mean it like that! You see...
あぁ そんなつもりじゃ… そのぉ
今日が最後の休日で だから
見ておきたかったんです エリア11を
Today's the last day of my holiday.
That's why I wanted to see Area 11.
どんな所なのかなぁって
I wanted to know
what kind of place it was.
だったら 僕じゃなくって…
Well, you didn't need me for that...
いいえ 良かったです あなたで
No. I'm glad I could see it with you.
あはっ そうですか
Oh... You don't say.
スザクさん もう１箇所だけ
案内して頂けますか？
Suzaku, would you please
take me to one more place?
なんなりと お申しつけ下さい お姫様
Your wish is my command, milady.
Then take me to Shinjuku.
では シンジュクに
えっ！
私にシンジュクを見せて下さい
枢木スザクさん
Suzaku Kururugi...
Please show me Shinjuku.
CODE GEASS
Lelouch of the Rebellion
Lelouch?
ルルーシュ君
ん！
Do you have a moment?
今 いい？
Sure. What is it?
うん 何？
About that phone call the other day...
この前の電話の事なんだけど
Phone call?
電話？
You know... In the bathroom?
その… ほら バスルームで
Ah.
あぁ
Do you know what the caller I.D. was?
着信履歴って分からない？
ちょっと連絡を取りたくて
I wanted to contact them again.
It was a school number,
so I don't know...
学校のだからな 俺の方では…
はっ！
I see.
Yeah, I should have known.
そう そうよね やっぱり
That girl!!!
あの女！
ん… 何？　どうかした？
What? Is something wro...
ぬわぁー
あっ
はぁ！
No way!
嘘…
Um... What are you doing?
ねぇ
ん？
これは何？
Ah, what indeed?
あぁ… なんだろ？
To think I'd return to the homeland like this!
こんな形で本国に戻るとは
関わらねばよかった あんな女
I wish I'd never
involved the damned girl!
えーいっ
Are you insane?!
Just strolling around like this?!
バカかお前は ふらふら出歩くなっ
It's fine as long as I stay in the school,
isn't it? Don't speak to me to strictly!
いいだろ 学校の中くらい
堅い事言うな
You can't!
You don't belong here!
ダメだ お前はここでは部外者なんだぞ
I don't belong anywhere.
私は どこでもそうだ
ん…
What's with her?
なんだ あいつは？
Oh, is she doing it again today?
あぁ 今日も やっているのか
Again?
今日も？
うっふふ
I used my Geass to have her
mark the wall every day.
彼女には 毎日ここの壁に
印を付けるようギアスをかけた
Geass?
ギアス？
This power I have.
I heard it when we made our contract.
この力の事だ
契約の時に そう聞こえたが？
ふ…
You're testing how long it lasts?
持続時間のテストか？
I need to know the specs
of this weapon, don't I?
武器のスペックは理解するべきだろ
お前も わがままが過ぎると…
Don't act too selfish, or else...
Do you think it would work on me?
効くかな 私に
んうっ
Relax. You and I are accomplices.
安心しろ
お前と私は共犯者だ
私達の不利になるような事はしない
I won't do anything to endanger us.
ふん
The Shinjuku ghetto is finished.
シンジュクゲットーは もうおしまいです
やっと人が戻り始めていたんですが…
People were just starting to return to it.
ん…
Man... I figured they wouldn't
use R-G on the Elevens.
あーあ やっぱイレヴン相手じゃ
ＲＧは使ってないな
Hey, look! There are marks from
hummer rounds. Get a shot of it!
おい こっち ヒューマー弾の跡だ
あ ちょっと撮って
Gotcha!
わーってるよっ
Me next! Me!
次 俺な
俺も
This is true, right? This info about Zero?
本当なのだな？　ゼロの情報は
Yes, sir.
Lord Kewell contacted me.
はい キューエル卿からの連絡です
Right! Set up a cordon around
Shinjuku ghetto sector 4!
よし 非常線をシンジュクゲットー
第４区域に張れ
Roger, sir.
了解しました 代行
It's up to you now, Lord Kewell.
キューエル卿 あとは頼みますよぉ
ぬおっ
I wanted you to connect me with Lord Jeremiah,
but you look a little busy now.
ジェレミア卿に連絡を取って
もらいたかったが
それどころでは ないようだな
Get out of here,
you Britannian pigs!
出てけよ ブリタニアの豚どもっ
えっ
はっ
Stay here!
ここにいて
H-How dare a mere Eleven...
なっ なんだよ イレヴンのくせに
I'm Japanese! Don't call me an Eleven!
日本人だ イレヴンなんて言うな
What are you talking about?
You people lost! You're just a beaten dog!
何 言ってんだ お前ら うちに
負けたんだろ？　敗戦国の犬が
You damn Brits!
このブリキ野郎ぉー
Stop, please! No violence!
やめて下さい！　暴力は
Stay outta this!
邪魔すんなよ！
ああっ
That's...
こいつ…
Are you Suzaku Kururugi?
お前 枢木スザクか？
The guy who killed Clovis?
クロヴィスをやった枢木
Idiot! It was Zero who did it!
バカ！　やったのはゼロだろ
けっ こいつは ただの奴隷だよ
He's nothing but a slave.
Who cares about being
an honorary Britannian?
何が名誉ブリタニア人だ 嬉しそうに
You happily sold your pride,
your people, your own soul!
プライドも仲間も魂も売って
それでも日本人か！
You call yourself Japanese?!
You're wrong! I...
違う 僕は…
I'm not wrong!
違わねぇんだよ！
You Britannian lap dog...
このブリタニアの犬がぁー
あっ
ああ
どはっ…
Stop, please!
やめて下さい
くっ く…
I'm a trained soldier.
Don't make me fight my own people!
自分は訓練を受けた人間です
これ以上 同じ仲間で…
Like hell we're your people!
何が仲間だー
C'mon! Let it go.
おい もういいだろ
チッ この裏切り者が
Traitor!
Suzaku!
スザク
Are you all right?
大丈夫ですか？
Yes.
ええ
Well, I'M not okay!
Look at my Prime G and my LX-4!
大丈夫じゃないよ
僕のPrime-GとLX-4が…
Why'd you wait so long?! Dammit,
some honorary citizen you are!
遅いんだよ
ったく 名誉のくせに
Why'd you let 'em go?!
You should've killed them!
なんで逃がしたんだ やっちまえよ！
They've killed lots of Elevens too,
haven't they?!
どうせ 何人もイレヴンを
殺してきたんだろ？
Who do you think has taken care of you...
誰がお前を養っていると思ってんだよ
うっ
I will not allow you to
insult this man any more!
これ以上 この方を
侮辱する事は許しません
To use my Geass, I have to have
direct eye contact with the subject.
ギアスを使うには
相手の目を直接見る必要がある
Transparent objects like
eyeglasses present no problem.
眼鏡程度の透過率なら問題はない
Effective range is approximately 270 meters.
有効距離は270メートルほど
It also appears that the subject has no memory of
events before, during, or after the power is used.
また ギアスをかけた前後及び
発動中には記憶の欠落が見られる
I believe this is due to damage caused by the
Geass interfering with the subject's cerebrum.
これは ギアスが大脳に介入した為に
生じたダメージと思われる
And if it's an optical signal,
I can reflect it as well.
光情報だとすれば反射も可能
You've investigated it a lot
in the short time you've had it.
これだけの短期間に よく調べたものだ
My opponent is an empire which
controls 1/3 of the entire world.
相手は
世界の３分の１以上を占める帝国だ
There's no such thing
as being too careful.
慎重過ぎるって事はない
I'd understand if you were an Eleven,
but you're Britannian, aren't you?
イレヴンならともかく お前は
ブリタニア人だろう？
This opponent may be too large and
strong to fight with just a Geass.
ギアス１つで戦うには
あまりに大きく 強い相手だ
Is it good to be strong?
強ければいいのか？
Is it bad to be weak?
弱い事は いけない事なんだろうか
Back then, when I was 10,
the world seemed like such a sad place.
あの頃… 10歳の僕らには
世界は とても悲しいものに見えた
Starvation...
飢餓
Disease...
病気
Filth... Corruption...
汚職 腐敗
Discrimination.
差別
War and terrorism.
戦争とテロリズム
The unending cycle of hatred.
繰り返される憎しみの連鎖
Repeating the same stupidity, again and again.
愚かなイタチごっこだ
Somebody has to break the cycle.
誰かが この連鎖を
断ち切らなくてはならない
理想だな
How idealistic.
Of course, I doubt anyone will be able
to make all the bad things go away.
もちろん そうしたものが
全て 無くせるなんて思わない
I'm not that arrogant. And so...
俺はそこまで 傲慢じゃない だから…
I don't want anyone to lose
any more loved ones.
大切な人を失わなくて済む
せめて 戦争のない世界に
To at least have a world without war.
And to gain such a favorable world...
そんな都合のいい世界…
How would you do it?
どうすれば
Simple.
簡単だ
When somebody wins,
the fighting will end.
誰かが勝てば戦いは終わる
Somebody?
誰か？
I don't know how it should be done.
僕には まだ分からない
But if I stop trying, then my father's
death will have been in vain.
でも 目指す事をやめたら父さんは
無駄死に になってしまう
Prime Minister Kururugi's?
枢木首相の？
My father had to die in the war!
あの戦争で 父さんは
死ななければ ならなかった
あ…
あっ
Jeremiah! You're going to pay for letting
Prince Clovis's murderer go free!
ジェレミア！
クロヴィス殿下殺害犯を取り逃がした責
その身で あがなってもらうぞ！
Kewell, you coward! That sighting
of Zero was a lie, wasn't it?!
卑怯な キューエル
ゼロ発見とは偽りか！
We have to wipe away our disgrace before
Princess Cornelia takes up her post here!
コーネリア殿下がご着任あそばす前に
身内の恥は すすがねばならん
Jeremiah! This is how we deal
with the traitors among us!
ジェレミア これが粛清だ！
Suzaku!
スザク君
Miss Cécile!
セシルさん
It's dangerous here! Get in!
ここは危険よ 乗って！
The Purebloods are having a squabble.
Let's get out of here!
純血派の内ゲバなんだよ
とっとと逃げよ
Oh, too bad about your acquittal.
あぁ それと 釈放残念でした
また付き合ってもらうよ
Now you have to work for me again.
Wait, please!
待って下さい
Isn't this a chance to get
battle data for the Lancelot?
ランスロットの戦闘データを取る
チャンスではないでしょうか？
え？
Oh, ho...
ほっほう
Suzaku...
スザク
I'm sorry, Euphy.
We have to say goodbye here.
ごめん ユフィ ここでお別れだ
I have to do this. I think I can stop
them with the Lancelot. That's why I!
僕は行かなきゃならない
ランスロットなら止められるはずだから
だから…
Dammit! Four against one!
くそっ ４人がかりとは
Cowards!
卑怯者！
Don't worry, Jeremiah!
We'll say you died in battle.
案ずるな ジェレミア
戦死扱いにしてやる
家の名前に傷はつかん
Your family's name won't be disgraced!
You're serious?
本気なのか？　本気で この私を…
You're serious about killing me?!
KEWELL!
キューエル！
Silence, Orange!
Why do you think we're here?!
黙れ！　オレンジ
我らは なんの為に存在している？
皇室の為であろう
To serve the imperial family!
All hail Britannia!
オールハイル ブリタニアー
Wha?!
なっ…
Stop it! You're all Britannian soldiers!
やめて下さい！
同じブリタニア軍同士で
That's... That honorary Britannian's!
あれは 名誉ブリタニア人の…
The advanced prototype
weapon, Lancelot!
嚮導兵器 ランスロット！
What does the Special Corps want here?!
Anyone who interferes will die!
特派が何用だ？
介入するなら誰であろうと討つ
No!
ダメです
I can't ignore this meaningless battle!
意味のない戦いを
見過ごす訳には いきません！
MVSs! They've perfected them?!
ＭＶＳ？　実用化されていたのか
だが… 今さら引けぬ
However, I won't withdraw now!
We're on the same side!
仲間同士で
Suzaku Kururugi... is saving ME?!
私を助ける？
枢木スザクが？
We can at least kill Orange!
ならばオレンジだけでも
ぬぅー
Lord Jeremiah!
ジェレミア卿！
Villetta! Thanks!
ヴィレッタか？　すまん
Still want to fight?!
まだ やるつもりですか？
はっ はっ はっ
Everyone, fall back.
皆 下がれ
Kewell!
キューエル
You understand, then?
分かって頂けましたか
I'm using a chaos mine.
ケイオス爆雷を使う
えっ？
STOP!
おやめなさーい！
はっ
What?!
何？
はっ
ぐっ ううっ…
ううっ
That honorary Britannian...
He risked his life for!
あの名誉ブリタニア人 身をていして
Everyone, lower your weapons!
双方とも 剣を納めなさい
あっ
In my name, I command you!
我が名において 命じさせて頂きます
It... can't be...
ま… まさか
I am Euphemia li Britannia,
third princess of Britannia!
わたくしはブリタニア第三皇女
ユーフェミア・リ・ブリタニアです
へっ？
ユフィ？
Euphy?
I'm assuming command here!
Now move back!
この場は わたくしが預かります
下がりなさい
It is her. The princess...
やはり 皇女殿下
Did you know her, Lloyd?
知ってました ロイドさん？
Yeah. She's been a student,
so she's never been seen in public, though.
うん 学生だからって
表には出てなかった人だけどねぇ
まっ 誠に
We... Truly...
We're truly sorry, Your Highness!
誠に申し訳ございません
Princess!
皇女殿下
えっ？
I had no idea who you were! Forgive me!
知らぬ事とはいえ 失礼いたしました
Suzaku... Just as you lost your father,
I have lost my brother, Clovis.
スザク あなたが父を失ったように
わたくしも 兄クロヴィスを失いました
は…
Will you help me to ensure that no one
ever has to lose a loved one again?
これ以上
みんなが大切な人を失わなくて済むよう
力を貸して頂けますか？
Yes! I don't deserve your kind words!
はっ もったいなき お言葉
ふっ
I heard what you did, Euphemia.
You shouldn't be so reckless.
聞いたぞ ユーフェミア
あまり無茶はするな
Forgive me, Sister. But...
申し訳ありません お姉さま しかし…
Call me viceroy here,
Sub-Viceroy Euphemia.
ここでは総督と呼べ
ユーフェミア副総督
The distinction is necessary
between direct sisters like us.
実の兄弟であればこそ けじめが必要だ
Yes. I understand.
はい 分かりました
Mm... Now then, your report?
うん
で そちの話だが
Yes, Highness. We've arranged a
welcome party for Your Highness, and...
はっ
聖庁にて 皇女殿下の歓迎の準備が
整っておりますので…
なっ
へっ
Sloppy. Senile. Corrupt.
抜けている 呆けている 堕落している
What about Zero?!
Capture the enemy of the Empire!
ゼロはどうした
帝国臣民の敵を捕まえろ！
GET ZERO!
ゼロを！
えっ！
I'll be joining you all here at
Ashford Academy starting today.
本日付けをもちまして
このアッシュフォード学園に
入学する事になりました
I'm Suzaku Kururugi.
It's a pleasure to meet you.
枢木スザクです
よろしくお願いします
Yukedomo kemonomichi
Walking along the animal path
行けどもけものみち 獅子よ虎よと吠え
Shishi yotorayoto hoe
Roaring with the lions and tigers
茜射す空の 彼方にまほろば
Akane sasu sora no kanata ni mahoroba
Paradise lying far across a sky dyed red
Yuushuu no kodoku ni samayou seishun wa
To a youth wandering, imprisoned in loneliness
幽囚の孤獨に 彷徨う青春は
Yowasato ikari ga sugata naki teki desu ka
Are weakness and hatred shapeless enemies?
弱さと怒りが姿無き敵ですか
Chichi yo madaware wa
Oh father, I am still...
父を 未だ我は
Onore wo shirigatashi
Learning who I am
己を知りがたし
Sakidatsu anira no
As I pursue the backs I no longer see
先立つ兄らの
Mienai senakawo oeba
Of the elder brothers who have gone before me
見えない背中を追えば
Mayoi no hitoyo ni
In the night I spend lost
迷いの一夜に明星は誘う
Myoujou wa izanau
The morning star beckons to me
Shi shite owaranu
This will not end in my death
死して終わらぬ
Yume wo kogaredomo
I long for my dream
夢を焦がれども
Tashika na kimi kosowaga inochi
My faith in you sustains my life
確かな君こそ我が命
Reppu no kouya de
In the windswept wilderness
烈風の荒野で 蝶よ花よと生き
Chou yo hanayoto iki
Living with the butterflies and flowers
Tokoshie no haru ni sakisou maboroshi
Blooming together in a mirage of eternal Spring
とこしえの春に 咲き添うまぼろし
Kondaku nojunketsu
If my purity seems muddied
混濁の純潔 この身は汚れても
Kono mi wayogoretemo
And my body seems filthy
Kokoro no nishiki wo shinjiteite kudasai
Please believe in the finery within my heart
心の錦を信じていてください
Hahayo kesshite ware wa namidawo misene domo
Oh mother, I will show no tears
母よ けして我は
涙を見せねども
Ashimoto no
They vanish like...
足下の草に露は消えもせで
Kusa ni tsuyu wa kiemosede
The dew in the grass beneath my feet
あぁ 分かっている
Yes, I understand. I'm lying.
俺は嘘をついている
To Shirley and Rivalz and the others.
Even to Suzaku and Nunnally.
シャーリーやリヴァル達に
スザクやナナリーにまでも
でも もう戻れない 帰れない
But there's no going back now.
I can't turn back.
C.C.が共犯者だというなら
それに乗るまでだ
While C.C. and I are accomplices,
I have to keep at this.
もう 自分に嘘はつきたくないから
Because I don't want
to lie to myself anymore.